(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
So everything that makes me whole
今君に捧げよう
I will offer it all to you now
I'm yours
My Dearest
Lyrics, Music: ryo (supercell)
ねえ
Hey
こんなに笑えたこと
Having been able to laugh this much
生まれて初めてだよ
Is a first since I was born
きっと
Surely
私はね
I, you see,
この日の
For this day
ために間違いだらけの
To walk down a path
道を歩いてきたんだ
That was full of mistakes
ずっと
Always
一人で
All alone
遠く遠くどこまでも遠く
Far, far away, as far as it goes
君と二人手を取って
Hand in hand with you
永遠にどこまでだって行けるはず
We should be able to go anywhere for eternity
もう一人じゃないと
Thinking I'm no longer alone
みわたせば
If I look around...
また笑って
...and you smile again...
守るべき大事なものが今あって
There is something important I must protect now
だけどなすすべもなく立ち尽くす時は
But when I stand still with no way to act
可能性を失って暗闇が君を
When you lose all possibility and darkness
覆い隠し絶望に飲み込まれるそんな時は
Covers you and you're swallowed by despair
私が君を照らす明かりになるから
I will be the light that illuminates you
たとえこの世界の王にだって消せはしない
Even for the king of this world, it won't be extinguished
So, everything that makes me whole
今君に捧げよう
I'll dedicate it to you now
I'm Yours
ねぇ この世界にはたくさんの
Hey, in this world there is so much
幸せがあるんだね
happiness, isn't there?
いつか二人なら
If it's the two of us someday...
誰かが君のことを嘘つきと呼んで
Someone calls you a liar
心ない言葉で傷つけようとしても
And tries to hurt you with heartless words
世界が君のことを信じようともせずに
Even if the world refuses to believe in you
茨の冠を被せようとしても
And tries to put a crown of thorns on you
私は君だけの味方になれるよ
I can be your only ally
その孤独痛みを私は知っている
I know that loneliness and pain
So, everything that makes me whole
今君に捧げよう
I'll dedicate it to you now
I'm Yours
いつか私を知ることができたなら
If you are able to know me someday
必ずその場所に私はいるから
I'll definitely be in that place
そこに希望の欠片すらなかったとしても
Even if there wasn't even a fragment of hope there
私があってはならないものであっても
Even if I'm something that shouldn't exist
君は忘れないでいてくれることを
Please don't forget that you will...
誰よりも私がそのことを知ってる
I know that better than anyone
だから私君のために全てを今
So for your sake, I'll now... all...
捧げよう
dedicate to you
鉄の弾が正義の証明
An iron ball is proof of justice
貫けば英雄に近づいた
If it pierces through, you've come closer to being a hero
その目を閉じて触れてみれば
If you close your eyes and try to touch it
同じ形 同じ体温の悪魔
It's a devil of the same shape and temperature
僕はダメで あいつはいいの？
I'm no good but they're okay?
そこに壁があっただけなのに
Even though there was just a wall there
生まれてしまった運命嘆くな
Don't lament the fate you were born into
僕らはみんな自由なんだから
Because we're all free
悪魔の子
Lyrics, Music: ヒグチアイ
The Devil's Child
Lyrics, Music: Ai Higuchi
鳥のように羽があれば
If I had wings like a bird
どこへだって行けるけど
I could go anywhere
帰る場所がなければきっと
But if I have no place to return to
どこへも行けない
I'm sure I won't be able to go anywhere
ただただ生きるのは嫌だ
I just don't want to simply exist
世界は残酷だ
The world is cruel
それでも君を
Even so, I...
君を愛すよ
I love you
何を犠牲にしても
No matter what I sacrifice
それでも君を守るよ
I will still protect you
間違いだとしても
Even if it's a mistake
疑ったりしない
I won't doubt it
正しさとは自分のこと
Righteousness is about yourself
強く信じることだ
believing strongly.
鉄の雨が降り頻る情景
A scene where iron rain falls incessantly.
テレビの中、映画に見えたんだ
It looked like a movie on TV.
戦争なんて愚かな凶暴
War is just foolish violence.
関係ない、知らない国の話
It's irrelevant, a story from an unknown country.
それなら何で、あいつを憎んで
Then why do I hate that person
黒い気持ち隠しきれない
and can't hide these dark feelings?
訳、説明だってできやしないんだ
I can't even explain the reason.
僕らはなんて矛盾ばかりなんだ
How full of contradictions we are.
この言葉も訳されれば
If these words were translated,
本当の意味は伝わらない
the true meaning wouldn't be conveyed.
信じるのは、その目を開いて
What I believe in is, opening those eyes
触れた世界だけ
only the world you've touched.
ただただ生きるのは嫌だ
I just hate living pointlessly.
世界は残酷だ
The world is cruel.
それでも君を愛すよ
But I still love you.
何を犠牲にしても
No matter what I sacrifice
それでも君を愛すよ
But I still love you.
それでも君を守るよ
I will still protect you.
選んだ人の影、捨てた者の屍
The shadows of the chosen, the corpses of the discarded.
気づいたんだ自分の中
I realized that inside me
育つのは悪魔の子
is the child of a devil growing.
正義の裏、犠牲の中
Behind justice, amidst sacrifice
心には悪魔の子
there's a devil's child in the heart.
Hi-RyS! It's IRyS from hololive English -Promise-.
hololive Englishのアイリスです！
I'm IRyS from hololive English!
Welcome to my 3rd anniversary live, "Devil Wears Hope"! Whoo!
I know it's a little late due to scheduling issues, but I'm so glad I'm finally able to do this! Yay!
えっと、ウェルカム、アイリスの、えっと、Devil Wears Hope、えっと、3周年のライブへようこそ！
Um, welcome to IRyS's... um, Devil Wears Hope... um, 3rd anniversary live! Welcome!
Thank you very much for coming. 来てくださりありがとうございます！
Thank you very much for coming. Thank you for coming!
Ha ha! How'd you guys like the first two songs?
Yes, my dear Nakaman-ko! Did you guys notice that they were held on different stages? Yeah?
「悪魔の子」と "My Dearest"、どうでしたか？
How did you like "Akuma no Ko" and "My Dearest"?
両方とも、あのなんと、別のステージで歌ってたんじゃないかなって、今頃みんな気づいてるんじゃないかな？
Both were... um, actually sung on different stages. I think everyone is noticing that by now.
Yeah, this—where I am right now—is the devil stage. It's very pretty and purple.
And over there is where the beautiful angelic stage is. Yes!
I will be moving around quite a lot this live to sing many songs.
And even though there's two stages, there might be even more!
なんとね、このあのダブルステージでお披露目させていただきます。というかダブルステージどころか、もっとあるかもしれません。
Actually, I'll be performing on this double stage. Or rather, instead of just a double stage, there might be even more.
歌うところね。楽しみにしてて下さい。
Places to sing, I mean. Please look forward to it.
えっと、As you guys can tell by now...
Um, as you guys can tell by now...
the theme of this live this time is Angel and Devil theme, because there's no other theme that would fit me as perfectly as this.
えっと、今回のライブのテーマはなんと、天使と悪魔です！多分今頃もうみんな気づいてると思うんですけど。
Um, the theme of this live is... wow, Angel and Devil! I think everyone's already noticed by now, though.
アイリスはね、えっと、半分悪魔、半分天使なんでね。そちらをね、あの、もう、パーフェクトなライブになるかと思います！
IRyS is, um, half-devil and half-angel. With that, I think it's going to be a perfect live!
I will be singing a lot of songs with a lot of guests, and there might be a very special announcement!
So I hope you guys look forward to that, yeah? Make sure you watch till the end.
And make sure you use the hashtag #DevilWearsHope to tweet your thoughts. Thank you!
ぜひね、こちらの #DevilWearsHope のハッシュタグでツイート、感想をお待ちしております！ありがとうございます！
Please, I'm waiting for your tweets and thoughts with this #DevilWearsHope hashtag! Thank you very much!
...続けてお願いします。
...Please continue.
えっとね、
Um...
この後たくさんの曲をたくさんのステージでね、
After this, I'll sing many songs on many stages,
たくさんのゲストと最後まで歌いますんで、みんな最後まで見てね。
with many guests until the end, so please watch until the end.
あとね、それどころからもうね、
And also, even more than that,
あのとっても素敵なね、
there's a very wonderful...
あの告知も最後の方にあるんで、
announcement towards the end,
最後まで見てください！
so please watch until the end!
では、Please... Oh, I have to go to the next stage again to sing more songs.
Well, please... Oh, I have to go to the next stage again to sing more songs.
では、Be right back! Yeah!
So, I'll be right back! Yeah!
Off to the next stage!
Estia casa misti fidi adora
to the beginning / Lyrics, Music: 梶浦由記
to the beginning / Lyrics, Music: Yuki Kajiura
あと一度だけ 奇跡は起こるだろう
Just one more time, a miracle will happen, I'm sure
優しい声で描く 歪んだ未来
The distorted future drawn by a gentle voice
もう誰も泣かない世界のために
For the sake of a world where no one cries anymore
紅く汚された空のどこにも
Nowhere in the crimson-stained sky
届かず消える 叫びと祈り
Cries and prayers that vanish without reaching
慰めさえすべてを裏切る
Even comfort betrays everything
きれいな月光の光が 始まりへと沈み行く
The beautiful moonlight sinks towards the beginning
その彼方へ 閉ざされて行く瞳で
Towards that far-off place, with eyes that are closing
まだ遠くへ手を伸ばす
Still reaching out into the distance
君の嘆きを
Towards your grief
信じて
Believe in it
本当は誰か 救いたくて
Wishing in truth to save someone
迷う心が空に穴を穿つ
This wandering heart bores a hole into the sky
君を選んで二人で行く
Choosing you, the two of us go on
喜びを探しながら
While searching for joy
どんな冷たい焔に身を焼かれても
No matter how cold the flames that burn us
微笑みの近く
Close to a smile
のたうつ夢
A writhing dream
命の意味を
The meaning of life
振り翳して この世界を
Brandishing it, this world
真夏の闇の中へ 返したい
I want to return it to the darkness of midsummer
哀しみだけ消せはしない
Grief alone cannot be erased
そんな人の心の
Of such a human heart
理さえこの手で切り裂いて
Even the laws, with these hands I'll tear them apart
きれいな月光の光は
The beautiful moonlight
ただ静かに 始まりへと朽ちて行くよ
Just quietly decays towards the beginning
閉ざされた憧れは まだ遠くへ
The closed-off longing is still far off
闇の中 君と生きた
In the darkness, I lived with you
日々の姿
The form of those days
優しい歌
A gentle song
Misti aso sarti o ria
My Soul, Your Beats!
Lyrics, Music: 麻枝 准
Lyrics, Music: Jun Maeda
目覚めては繰り返す 眠い朝は
Waking up and repeating those sleepy mornings...
襟のタイをきつく締め
Tightening the tie on my collar
教室のドアくぐると ほんの少し
Passing through the classroom door, just a little...
胸を張って歩き出せる
I can puff out my chest and start walking
そんな日常に 吹き抜ける風
In such daily life, a wind blows through
聞こえた気がした
I felt like I heard it
感じた気がしたんだ
I felt like I sensed it
震え出す 今この胸で
Starting to tremble, now in this chest
もう来る気がした
I felt like it's coming soon
幾億の星が消え
Seeing hundreds of millions of stars vanish...
去ってくのを
...as they fade away
見送った
I saw them off
手を振った
I waved my hand
よかったねと
Saying, "I'm glad"
廊下の隅見下ろす
Looking down at the corner of the hallway
掃除の途中
While cleaning
おかしなものだと
I think it's a strange thing
思う
Indeed
あたしの中の時は
Even though time inside of me
止まってるのに
Has stopped
違う日々を
As if I'm living
生きてるように
Through different days
埃は雪の
The dust piles up
ように降り積む
Just like snow
待ってる気がした
I felt like I was waiting
呼んでる気がしたんだ
I felt like I was being called
震え出す 今この時が
Starting to tremble, now this moment...
見つけた気がした
I felt like I found it
失われた記憶が
Lost memories
呼び覚ました
Have awakened
物語
A story
永遠の
Eternal
その終わり
And its end
いつの間にか
Before I knew it
駆け出してた
I had started running
あなたに手を
My hand was
引かれてた
Being pulled by you
昨日は遠く
Yesterday is far away
明日はすぐ
Tomorrow is right here
そんな当たり前に
At such an obvious thing
心が躍った
My heart danced
聞こえた気がした
I felt like I heard it
感じた気がしたんだ
I felt like I sensed it
震え出す 今この胸で
Starting to tremble, now in this chest
もう来る気がした
I felt like it's coming soon
幾千の朝を越え
Crossing over thousands of mornings
新しい陽が
A new sun...
待ってる気がした
I felt like I was waiting
呼んでる気がしたんだ
I felt like I was being called
震えてる この魂が
Trembling, this soul of mine
見つけた気がした
I felt like I found it
幾億の夢のように
Like hundreds of millions of dreams
消え去れる日を
On the day I can vanish
見送った
I saw them off
手を振った
I waved my hand
ありがとうと
Saying, "Thank you"
メフィスト
Lyrics, Music: 薔薇園アヴ
Mephisto
Lyrics, Music: Avu-chan
誰かに化けて...
Disguised as someone else...
ラストチャンスに飢えたつま先が
My toes, starved for one last chance...
踊り出すまま駆けたこの夜空
...dashed through the night sky as they danced.
並のスタンスじゃ靡かない
With an ordinary stance, I won't sway.
星は宝石の憧れ
The stars are the envy of jewels.
浮かぶ涙と汗は血の名残り
The floating tears and sweat are the remains of blood.
目の中でしか泳げない芝居
A play that can only swim within the eyes.
だけどステージが逃がさない
But the stage won't let go.
いついつまでも憧れ
Always and forever, a longing.
焦がれているよ
I'm yearning for it.
I've never seen such a liar.
生まれつきだっての底なし
Born with a bottomless nature.
This lie is love. And this lie is a gift to the world.
誰と生きたか思い出して
Remember who you lived with.
わたしが命を掛けるから
Because I'll put my life on the line...
あげるから
...I'll give it to you.
あなたは時間をくれたのでしょう？
You gave me your time, didn't you?
あらゆる望みのすべてを叶えたら
If all of every desire is fulfilled...
あぁ果たせたら
Ah, if they could be realized...
あなたに会いたい
I want to see you.
星に願いをかけて
Making a wish upon a star.
戻れないから大切にするの
I'll treasure it because there's no going back.
始めないなら高を括れるよ
If I don't start, I can underestimate it.
楽になる日は末代
The day it gets easier is generations away.
日々の中に集まる
Gathering within the days...
悲しい光
...is a sorrowful light.
生まれつきだせば底なし
If born into it, it's bottomless.
This lie is love. And this lie is a gift to the world.
誰を活きたか忘れちゃった！
I've forgotten who I lived as!
あなたに命が戻るなら 届くなら
If life returns to you, if it reaches you...
わたしはどうなろうと構わないのに
...I wouldn't care what happens to me.
どうやら総ては叶わない
Apparently, not everything will come true.
叶わないならば
If it won't come true...
あなたになりたい
...then I want to become you.
星は耽け耽る
The stars grow deeper and deeper.
わたしが命を
I will...
掛けるから あげるから
...put my life on the line, I'll give it to you.
あなたは時間をくれたのでしょう？
You gave me your time, didn't you?
あらゆる望みのすべてを叶えたら
If all of every desire is fulfilled...
あぁ果たせたら
Ah, if they could be realized...
あなたに会いたい
I want to see you.
星に願いをかけて
Making a wish upon a star.
さあ星の子たちよ よくお眠りなさい
Now, children of the stars, sleep well.
輝きは鈍らない あなたたちならば
The brilliance won't dull, if it's you all.
さあ星の子たちよ よく狙いなさい
Now, children of the stars, aim well.
またたきを許さない あなたたちならば
I won't allow a flicker, if it's you all.
撲殺天使ドクロちゃん
Bludgeoning Angel Dokuro-chan
ぴぴるぴるぴるぴぴるぴ〜
Pipiru piru piru pipiru pi~
何でもできちゃうバット エスカリボルグ〜
The bat that can do anything, Excaliborg~
何でもできちゃうバット エスカリボルグ
The bat that can do anything, Excaliborg
ぴぴるぴるぴるぴぴるぴ〜
Pipiru piru piru pipiru pi~
魔法の擬音で人生やり直してあげる
I'll let you start your life over with magical onomatopoeia.
いやん よだめよ こんなの バカバカ
Oh no, you mustn't, this is... Stupid, stupid!
そんなにギラギラしないで
Don't be so glaring.
お願い 痛くしちゃ えい！
Please, don't make it hurt... Hyah!
撲殺天使 血飛沫ドクドク ドクロちゃん
Bludgeoning Angel, blood-splattering doku doku Dokuro-chan.
撲殺天使 心臓ドクドク ドクロちゃん
Bludgeoning Angel, heart-pounding doku doku Dokuro-chan.
踏んで 縛って 叩いて
Step on me, tie me up, hit me.
蹴って 濡らして 潰して
Kick me, soak me, crush me.
でも それって ボクの「愛」なの
But that's just my "love".
ぴぴるぴるぴるぴぴるぴ〜
Pipiru piru piru pipiru pi~
万能血まみれバット エスカリボルグ〜
All-purpose blood-stained bat, Excaliborg~
万能血まみれバット エスカリボルグ
All-purpose blood-stained bat, Excaliborg
ぴぴるぴるぴるぴぴるぴ〜
Pipiru piru piru pipiru pi~
不思議な擬音で夢 叶えてあげる
I'll grant your dream with mysterious onomatopoeia.
いやん バカァ〜ん ダメダメ
Oh no, silly~ You mustn't.
そんなにムラムラしないで
Don't be so restless.
お願い...
Please...
お願いだから
Please, I'm begging you
エイ！
Ay!
撲殺天使
Bludgeoning Angel
バットでドスドスドクロちゃん
Mashing you with a bat, Dokuro-chan
撲殺天使
Bludgeoning Angel
血みどろどろどろドクロちゃん
Gory, gory Dokuro-chan
斬って
Slash
殴って
Hit
刺して
Stab
晒して
Expose
垂らして
Drip
でもそれってボクの「愛」なの
But that's just my "love"
ぴぴるぴるぴるぴぴるぴ～
Pipiru piru piru pipiru pi~
天才ピコピコハンマー
Genius squeaky hammer
エスカリボルグ！
Excaliborg!
ぴぴるぴるぴるぴぴるぴ～
Pipiru piru piru pipiru pi~
やわいいお耳で人生
Life with soft ears
ドキドキバクバク
Heart pounding
はふんひいパプ
Hafun hii papu
許して
Forgive me
そんなにギトギトしないで
Don't be so greasy
お願いだから
Please, I'm begging you
エイ！
Ay!
撲殺天使
Bludgeoning Angel
血祭りドンドコドクロちゃん
Bloodbath dondoko Dokuro-chan
撲殺天使
Bludgeoning Angel
鼻血ドピュドピュドクロちゃん
Nosebleed dopyu dopyu Dokuro-chan
剥いて
Peel
抱いて
Hold
閉じ込めて
Shut you in
泣いて
Cry
笑って
Laugh
殺して
Kill me
でもそれってボクの「愛」なの
But that's just my "love"
撲殺天使
Bludgeoning Angel
バットでドスドスドクロちゃん
Mashing you with a bat, Dokuro-chan
撲殺天使
Bludgeoning Angel
血みどろどろどろドクロちゃん
Gory, gory Dokuro-chan
斬って
Slash
殴って
Hit
刺して
Stab
晒して
Expose
垂らして
Drip
でもそれってボクの「愛」なの
But that's just my "love"
ぴぴるぴるぴるぴぴるぴ～
Pipiru piru piru pipiru pi~
この世で造花より綺麗な花は無いわ
In this world, no flower is more beautiful than a fake flower
何故ならば総ては嘘で出来ている
Because everything is made of lies
antipathy world
フォニイ
Lyrics, Music: ツミキ
Phony
Lyrics, Music: Tsumiki
絶望の雨はあたしの傘を突いて
The rain of despair pokes at my umbrella
湿らす前髪とこころの裏面
Dampening my bangs and the back of my heart
煩わしいわ
How bothersome
何時しか言の葉は疾うに枯れきって
Before long, words had already withered away
事の実があたしに触れている
And the truth of the matter is touching me
鏡に映り嘘を描いて
Drawing a lie reflected in the mirror
自らを見失った成れの果て
The end result of losing sight of oneself
パッパッパラッパパパラパ
Pa-pa-pa-ra-pa-pa-pa-ra-pa
謎謎 かぞえて遊びましょう
Riddles, riddles, let's play by counting them
タッタラタッタラタッタラタ
Ta-ta-ra-ta-ta-ra-ta-ta-ra-ta
何故何故 此処で踊っているでしょう
Why, oh why, am I dancing here?
簡単な事も解らないわ
I don't even understand simple things
あたしって何だっけ
What was I again?
それすら夜の手の解されて
Even that is unraveled by the hands of the night
愛の様に 消える 消える
Like love, it vanishes, vanishes
さよならも言えぬ儘泣いた
I cried without even being able to say goodbye
フォニイ フォニイ フォニイ
Phony, phony, phony
嘘に絡まっているあたしはフォニイ
Entangled in lies, I am a phony
antipathy world
何時しか空の音が厭に鳴り合って
Before long, the sounds of the sky were grating against each other
色の目があなを解いている
Eyes of color are unraveling you
鏡に映るあたしを欠いて
Lacking the me reflected in the mirror
誰もが見間違った虚像
A virtual image that everyone mistook
如何して愛なんてものに群がり
Why do they flock to something like love
それを欲して生きるのだ
And live their lives wanting it?
今日も泳いでいる夜の電車が通り去っていく
Today, too, the night train swims by
踊り明かせよ
Dance the night away
パッパッパラッパパパラパ
Pa-pa-pa-ra-pa-pa-pa-ra-pa
謎謎 騙して歌いましょう
Riddles, riddles, let's sing while deceiving
タッタラタッタラタッタラタ
Ta-ta-ra-ta-ta-ra-ta-ta-ra-ta
何故何故 此処が痛むのでしょう
Why, oh why, does it hurt here?
嘘に絡まっている ただ
Just entangled in lies
簡単なことも解らないわ
I don't even understand simple things
あたしって何だっけ
Who was I again?
それすら夜の手ほどきされて
Even that is undone by the night's hand
愛のように消える
Vanishing like love
さよなら またねと呟いた
I whispered "goodbye, see you again"
フォニイ フォニイ フォニイ
Phony, phony, phony
嘘に絡まっている あたしは
I'm entangled in lies, I'm
フォニイ
a phony
造花だけが知っている
Only artificial flowers know
秘密のフォニイ
The secret phony
空想メソロギヰ
Fantasy Mythology
Consuetudo, Quod, Olim, Habebat, Retinebat, Et, Conservabat, In, Perpetuum, In, Aeternum...
微睡みの淵で
On the edge of slumber
まぶたにたゆとう
Drifting on my eyelids
無想の神は優雅に微笑み
The god of musou smiles elegantly
潮をくだし
Sending down the tide
時空を統べる因果の鎖は絡みだす
The chains of causality that rule space-time begin to entangle
神の与えし
Bestowed by God
空想プログラム
The fantasy program
Eins, zwei, drei! 重なり合う
Eins, zwei, drei! Overlapping
Eins, zwei, drei! 死を交わして
Eins, zwei, drei! Exchanging death
消滅の遊戯に 焦がれる奇跡を奪う
In the game of annihilation, stealing the yearned-for miracle
Survival game...
螺旋のように...
Like a spiral...
アイディスマイル
Identity Smile
交わる線と線
Intersecting lines
大好きなあれこれそれ
All the things I love
そういつだって 譲れないアイデンティティ
Yes, always, my unyielding identity
重なる円と円
Overlapping circles
深まる多分もっと face to face
Deepening probably more, face to face
ねえいつだって 飛び越えられないマイノリティ
Hey, always, the minority I can't jump over
進めない行き止まりでも
Even at a dead end I can't move past
繋いでたいなら 外せない秘密ごと
If I want to stay connected, the secrets I can't let go of
惹かれ合って存在する世界なら
If it's a world that exists by being drawn to each other
させたいなら ねえこのままで このままで いられるかな
If you want it to, hey, I wonder if we can stay like this, stay like this
淡い期待にどうしても
In faint expectations, inevitably
塞いで曖昧な表情を
Closing off my ambiguous expression
こうやって繋いでいられたなら
If we could be connected like this
天使と悪魔
Angel and Devil
大丈夫 大丈夫 きっとすべて上手くいくよ
It's okay, it's okay, I'm sure everything will be fine
やめようよ やめようよ 傷つくのはもう嫌だ
Let's stop, let's stop, I don't want to get hurt anymore
大丈夫 大丈夫 きっとすべて上手くいくよ
It's okay, it's okay, I'm sure everything will be fine
やめようよ やめようよ 傷つくのはもう嫌だ
Let's stop, let's stop, I don't want to get hurt anymore
耳元でささやく
Whispering in my ear
この心揺さぶる
Shaking this heart
私の心の中に 天使と悪魔がいる
Inside my heart, there's an angel and a devil
どちらにつくかはあなた次第だ
Which one to side with is up to you
後悔ないように 精々迷いなさい
So that you don't regret it, hesitate as much as you like
目を閉じて 両耳塞いだ
Close your eyes, plug both ears
私の心の中に 天使と悪魔がいる
Inside my heart, there's an angel and a devil
どちらを信じるかも自分自身だ
Which one to believe in is up to yourself
天国も地獄も 気の向くまま進め
Heaven or hell, move forward as you please
その場所で 自分らしくいられるかどうかだ
It's about whether you can be yourself in that place
自分らしく笑えるかどうかだ
It's about whether you can laugh like yourself
雪の華
Snow Flower
Lyrics: Satomi Music: 松本良喜
Lyrics: Satomi Music: Ryoki Matsumoto
伸びた影を
The shadows stretching
舗道にならべて
Out across the pavement
夕闇の中を
In the evening twilight
君と歩いてる
I'm walking with you
手をつないで
Holding hands
いつまでもずっと
Forever and ever
そばにいられたなら
If I could just stay by your side
泣けちゃうくらい
It's enough to make me cry
風が冷たくなって
The wind has grown cold
冬の匂いがした
And it smells like winter
そろそろこの街に
Soon, in this town...
君と近付ける季節がくる
...the season where I can be close to you will come
今年、最初の雪の華を
The first snow flowers of this year
2人寄り添って
As we draw close to each other
眺めているこの瞬間に
Watching them at this moment
シアワセがあふれだす
Happiness overflows
甘えとか弱さじゃない
It's not dependence or weakness
ただ、君を愛してる
I just love you
心からそう思った
I feel it from the bottom of my heart
君がいると
When you're with me
どんなことでも
No matter what happens
乗りきれるような気持ちになってる
I feel like I can overcome anything
こんな日々が
That days like these
いつまでもきっと
Will surely continue forever
続いていくことを祈っているよ
I am praying for that
風が窓を揺らした
The wind shook the window
夜は揺り起こして
Waking up the night
どんな悲しいことも
No matter how sad things are
僕が笑顔へと変えてあげる
I will change them into smiles for you
舞い落ちてきた雪の華が
The snow flowers that fluttered down
窓の外ずっと
Outside the window, all the while
降りやむことを知らずに
Without knowing how to stop falling
僕らの街を染める
They color our town
誰かのために何かを
Doing something for someone...
したいと思えるのが愛ということを知った
...I've learned that wanting to do that is what love is
もし君を失ったとしたなら
If I were to lose you
星になって君を照らすだろう
I would become a star and shine on you
笑顔も涙に濡れてる夜も
Both on nights of smiles and nights wet with tears
いつもいつでもそばにいるよ
I will always, always be by your side
今年、最初の雪の華を
The first snow flowers of this year
2人寄り添って
As we draw close to each other
眺めているこの瞬間に
Watching them at this moment
シアワセがあふれだす
Happiness overflows
甘えとか弱さじゃない
It's not dependence or weakness
ただ、君とずっと
I just want to stay with you forever
このまま一緒にいたい
Just as we are
素直にそう思える
I can honestly feel that way
この街に降り積もっていく
Accumulating in this town
真っ白な雪の華
Pure white snow flowers
2人の胸にそっと
Gently into our hearts
想い出を描くよ これからも君と
Drawing memories, from now on too, with you
想い出を描くよ
I'll paint our memories
これからもずっと...
From now on, and forever...
And that was Yuki no Hana.
Did you guys like the ballad and the gondola
riding all the way here?
Yes, it was a pretty flower...
...flower snowflake, yes, that I rode on all the way here.
And did you guys like the guest part? Yeah!
I sang a lot of songs with the guests and a full on
medley that I put a lot of thought into.
I really want to talk more about the medley and
the concept but I think I won't have enough time for that.
Maybe I'll talk about that in a future stream.
And also thank you so much for my lovely
guests for singing with me.
But there's still one more guest song! Yeah! And
that's not the last song by the way, so no worries.
There's going to be one more guest song that
you guys are absolutely gonna love!
And also, also!
There's going to be one super exciting announcement
that I've been waiting super waiting to show you guys.
So please do look forward to that as well.
なんとね、雪の華とあとゲストパートどうでしたか？
So, how did you like Yuki no Hana and the guest part?
いや、あのメドレーとかね、すごく、とてもあのもう色々考えた上で企画したんで、
I put a lot of thought into planning that medley and everything,
もう本当にね、色々自分の考えたこととかも全部言いたいんですけど、ちょっとそこまで時間ないので、
I really want to tell you all about my ideas, but I don't quite have the time for that here,
とにかくね、みんな気に入っていただけるととても嬉しいです。
Anyway, I'd be very happy if you all enjoyed it.
そしてね、あの素敵な先輩方と一緒に歌えてとっても嬉しかったです。
And I was so happy to sing with those wonderful senpais.
本当にありがとうございました、先輩方。
Thank you so much, senpais.
そして、えっと、まだね、ゲストパートというかあとゲスト曲まだ一曲あるんで、
And, well, there's still one more guest part—actually, one more guest song—
これから歌いますんでね、みんな最後まで見てください。
I'm going to sing it now, so please stay with me until the end.
あとね、そのすぐあとにね、もうひとつとっても素敵な、嬉しい、
And right after that, there's another very wonderful, happy announcement...
ずっと待ち遠しかった告知とお披露目があるんで、みんな最後まで見てくださいね。
...and reveal that I've been looking forward to for ages, so please watch until the very end.
では、次の曲行きます。Please listen to the next song.
Now, on to the next song. Please listen to the next song.
罪の名前
Crime of Name
Lyrics, Music: ryo (supercell)
お目目の女神様が目を留めた
A goddess with eyes caught sight
なんて可愛い赤ん坊だろう
What a cute baby
そうだわ あの子に魔法をかけて 遊びましょう
I know, let's put a spell on that child and play
くぼんだ両目 痩せ過ぎな体
Sunken eyes, a skeletal body
私を見れば 誰しもが言うのです
Anyone who looks at me says
化け物 お前は 同じ人間じゃないんだよと
"Monster, you're not a human like the rest of us."
悲しいなんて思わない だって
I don't think it's sad, because
思えば ほら また 涙があふれて 震える
When I think about it, look, tears overflow and I tremble
もしも願いが一つ叶うなら
If I could have one wish come true
世界でたった一人だけの友達を
I'd want just one friend in the whole world
生きることは素晴らしいこと
That living is a wonderful thing
そんな風に私も思ってみたい
I want to be able to think that way too
罪の名前
The Name of the Sin
ねずみはなんで嫌われるのでしょう
Why are mice so hated?
彼らは笑って「汚いからだろう」
They laugh and say, "Because they're dirty."
それなら答えて
If that's the case, then answer me
目のみえない僕のために
for the sake of my blind eyes.
見て見ぬふりに理不尽な差別
Turning a blind eye and unreasonable discrimination,
それでねずみと何が違うの
how is that any different from the mice?
嘲笑う彼らに続けて言うんだ
Tell those who mock you...
「二度とするな」
"Don't ever do that again."
嬉しいのになぜでしょうか
I'm happy, so why is it?
だって涙がほらやっぱり
Because, you see, tears are...
溢れてくるのです
...still overflowing.
もしかなりたいものになれるなら
If I could become anything I wanted,
あなたの前では普通の女の子に
I'd want to be just an ordinary girl in front of you.
思えば思うほどに胸が苦しい
The more I think about it, the more my heart aches.
どうして私は私なのでしょうか
Why must I be myself?
「君は優しい女の子なのに
"Even though you're a kind girl,
いつも自分を責める
you're always blaming yourself.
慰めてあげたい君を
I want to comfort you.
そうだ、ここに咲いた花を君に捧げよう
I know, I'll give you this flower that bloomed here.
それは見事な白いユリの花」
It's a magnificent white lily."
さあ、と君の近くに寄っていくよ
He says, and draws closer to you.
運命の女神様は意地悪だ
The Goddess of Fate is cruel.
醜いあの子を見たらどんな顔
What kind of face would she make
するんでしょう
if she saw that ugly child?
見物ね
It'll be quite a sight.
迷子、迷子な俺と魔法をかける
I, a lost soul, shall cast a spell.
花は黒く淀んだ色に染まる
The flower is dyed in a murky black color.
それは不吉な黒いユリの花
It's an ominous black lily.
「お前へこれから贈り物だ
"Here's a gift for you.
そら、血の匂いさ」
Look, it's the scent of blood."
ああ、これはきっと罰です
Ah, this must be my punishment.
だって私が身の程知らずに
Because I unknowingly...
恋をしたから
...fell in love.
いっそ、死んでしまえばいいのでしょう
I should probably just die.
あなたは叫ぶ「泣かないで、僕がずっと」
You shout, "Don't cry, I'll always..."
「死ぬまでそばにいるからさ」
"...be by your side until I die."
「今日から君は普通の女の子さ」
"From today on, you're just an ordinary girl."
「それに見えるよ」
"That's how you look to me."
悪夢のような魔法はほら
Look, the nightmare-like spell...
解けたみたい
...seems to have been broken.
And that was "Tsumi no Namae" with my Promise ladies!
Did you guys like it?
Let's just say that that was the last song—or I said that that was the last song, even though I did not say that a few minutes ago.
Ah, I think this live is over already! What should I do?
どうしようかな...
What should I do?
えーっ？
Ehh?
You guys want more?
しょうがないなあ！
Oh, fine then!
Or more like, I still have this exciting announcement to make!
Can you guys guess what it is?
Yeah! It is a new original song!
Yeah, it is a new song called "Twilight," written by Yunosuke-san,
with lyrics written by Gyuniku-san.
It is a really, really, really cool song, and...
...with a really, really cool MV that will be shown right after this live!
Yeah! So when you finish watching this,
please go directly straight to the MV,
'cause you will regret it if you don't.
It is a song that is based on this angel-devil theme
that this live is also based on, or more like I based the live's theme to the song.
So if you put them two together, it becomes a work of art! Yes.
But before you go to the MV after this, I will be performing...
Yes.
A one last song for you guys, which is obviously,
obviously TwiLight. I will be releasing... I will be performing
the song for you guys right after this. So I hope you guys enjoy that
as my last song for today. I will be saying this in Japanese now.
えっと、では、えっとね、なんと...
Well, so, actually...
新曲出します！TwiLightという曲になっています。
I'm releasing a new song! It's called TwiLight.
えっと、ゆのすけさんに書いていただき、えっと、歌詞は
It was composed by Yunosuke-san, and the lyrics were written by
えっと、牛肉さんに書いていただきました。
Gyūniku-san.
とってもね、カッコいい曲になっています。
It's a really cool song.
そしてなんとね、このライブのすぐあとに
And actually, right after this live,
その、めちゃくちゃいいMVをね、あの、出していただきますんで
they will be releasing a really amazing MV.
みんなこのライブのすぐあとに、そっちに飛んでいただけるととっても嬉しいです。
I'd be very happy if everyone could head over there right after the live.
その、新曲TwiLightは、えっと、天使と悪魔のこちらのライブのテーマに合わせた曲になっています。
The new song TwiLight matches the angel and devil theme of this live.
でね、えっと、最後もう一曲お披露目したいかと思うんですけど
So, I'd like to perform one last song for you...
なんとその新しい曲TwiLightを披露させていただきます。
and that will be the new song, TwiLight.
ではね、最後の曲、TwiLight聞いてください。
Now, please listen to the final song: TwiLight.
Please listen to my last song for today, and thank you so much for watching until the end.
Please listen to TwiLight.
Just as 私はいま
Just as I am now
私である事実も
The fact that I am myself
定められない 定まらない
Cannot be defined, is not defined
存在なら That’s fine with me
If that's my existence, that's fine with me
Heads or tails 保つだけじゃ意味なく
Heads or tails, there's no point in just maintaining
Heads or tails それだけじゃなく
Heads or tails, it's not just that
Fallen angel, Ascended devil
あらゆる姿を
Every form
求めーている
I'm seeking
享受する自由も ひとつの意志
The freedom to enjoy is also a will
求めーている
I'm seeking
自分をただ認めたい
I just want to accept myself
TwiLight 昂く拡がる
TwiLight, spreading high
刹那の黄昏よ
O, twilight of the moment
Try out 掛け違えても
Try out, even if things are misplaced
全ての指標だから
Because they are all indicators
深層の Back to back 奈落から高くまで
Deep down, back to back, from the abyss to the heights
昏くの声で 羽ばたいた
I spread my wings with a dark voice
大概の正体が 間違いで生まれる
Most identities are born from mistakes
存在じゃないのか
Aren't they existence?
関係性 すでに有無も同然
Relationships, already like existence or non-existence
High and low 無視の結論
High and low, the conclusion of ignoring
Fallen angel, Ascended devil
歪な形を
The distorted shape
求めーている
I'm seeking
浸した熱を 捩るように
As if twisting the soaked heat
一長一短は チグハグの定義なんて
Merits and demerits, the definition of being mismatched
主張なだけで
Is just an assertion
白と黒が 大切なのは
That white and black are important
わかるけど 私は
I understand, but I...
私はどこ 私は誰
Where am I? Who am I?
私は何者か
What am I?
私はいま 私はいま
I am now, I am now
私へと混ざり合うの
Mixing into myself
相反的な翼で
With conflicting wings
高くへと飛び立てば
If I fly high
曖昧なのも 潔く
Being ambiguous, cleanly
まとめて映るから
Because it's all reflected together
TwiLight 両手に乗せた
TwiLight, in both hands I hold
綯い交ぜを解く
Untying the mixture
Try out 掛け違えても
Try out, even if things are misplaced
生性は要らない
Correction is not needed
Be oneself, Be myself, Revisit ふたつで
Be oneself, Be myself, Revisit with two
Be oneself, Be myself, ひとつな
Be oneself, Be myself, one
Be oneself, Be myself, Revisit こころの
Be oneself, Be myself, Revisit the heart's
指標だから
Because it's the indicator
愛してる
I love you,
いつまでも
forever.
Thank you!
見に来てくれて
ありがとう！♡
Thank you for coming! ♡
Thank you so much for all of your support since my
debut over 3 years ago!
Your love & cheers are what made this live
possible & I will do my best to continue being...
...your ~ ANGEL ＆ DEVIL ~
...your ~ ANGEL & DEVIL ~